# Camilla Pacifici

#### Contact Information

Email: camilla.pacifici@gmail.com; cpacifici@stsci.edu - Github: camipacifici

## Highlights

Astronomer: interested in the formation and evolution of galaxies; spectral energy distribution fitting; star formation histories; dust. Project Scientist and Product Owner for the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) data analysis and visualization tools. Extensive experience with Scrum (Agile), Python, Jira, Confluence, Git, Tableau, Pandas. Excellent written and verbal communicator. Extensive experience in statistical analysis, modeling, data mining. Fluent in Italian, English, and French.

### Experience

June 2018 - present

Project Scientist and Product Owner for the JWST data analysis tools,

- · I manage priorities and backlog for the open-source package *jdaviz* and astronomy related libraries (*specutils*, *photuils*, and *specreduce*).
- · I interact with the scientific community and the stakeholders at NASA to define user stories and algorithms to satisfy their analysis and visualization needs.
- $\cdot$  I clear road blocks and make sure deliveries happen on time. I write documentation and set up datasets for testing.

June 2018 -September 2022 Instrument Scientist for JWST.

- · I wrote software to calibrate one if JWST instruments during commissioning.
- · I created simulations of JWST data and helped developed the data reduction pipeline.
- · I organized a series of webinars to teach the community how to use JWST data.

April 2012 -November 2017 Postdoc fellow in Germany, South Korea, and USA,

I worked with very large dataset, modeled and interpreted both spectroscopic and photometric data (I wrote software to translate data into galaxy physical parameters), and published  $\sim$ 70 refereed articles on the topic of galaxy formation and evolution.

#### Education

May 2012

PhD in Astronomy and Astrophysics, Sorbonne University, Paris, France.

December 2008

Laurea in Astrophysics (Master Degree), Università Milano-Bicocca, Milano, Italy.

October 2006

Laurea Triennale in Physics (Bachelor Degree), *Università Milano-Bicocca*, Milano, Italy, 110/110 cum laude.

## Skills

Project management

Communicate with stakeholders; define priorities; progress reports; clear road blocks; meet deadlines and deliveries; ensure positive workplace for team.

Programming

Python; git; Jupyter Notebooks and Lab; testing and debugging.

Communication

Effective communication with users, developers, and stakeholders; create material for demonstrations.

# Awards

- 2022 Agency Honor Award for the JWST Science Operations Team, NASA, US.
- 2021 STScI Leadership Award for chairing the JWebbinars, STScI, US.
- 2021 AURA Team Award for JWST user support, STScl, US.
- 2017 ISSNAF Young Investigators Award, Washington, DC, US.

# Qualifications

Dec 2024 Scrum training for Product Owner, Certified by BIG Agile, US.	Dec 2024	Scrum training f	for Product Owner,	Certified by	BIG Agile, US.
--	----------	------------------	--------------------	--------------	----------------

- Jan/2023 Abilitazione scientifica nazionale, Settore Concorsuale 02/C1 II Fascia.
- July 2024 Official Carpentries Instructor, Certified by Software Carpentries, US.
- December 2022 Project Management Essentials (Franklin Covey's), Certified by Accelebrate, US.
  - August 2019 Advanced Python, Certified by Software Carpentries, US.